Bohna Family Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bohna Family Correspondence
1882-1956
WA MSS S-2673
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.67
(4 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence to and from members of the Bohna family in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. The letters document daily life and family news of various members of the Bohna family (descendents of Christian Bohna), who were farmers, blacksmiths, and miners in Oregon and California (residing in, among other places, Kern County, California, and in Wasco and Clackamas Counties, Oregon). In addition to members of the Bohna family, principal correspondents include Spurrell W. Woody and other members of the Woody family, of Woody, California.
Bohna family
Bohna, James E.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Charles Apfelbaum on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Bohna Family
Christian Bohna (1805-1872) was born in Germany and immigrated to the United States in the 1830s. After the death of his first wife Polly, he remarried (to Ophelia née Greene) and moved west with his many children, first settling in Kern County, California in 1859, and then in Oregon in 1862. Christian Bohna had twelve children: Hannah, Edward, Mary, Thomas, Henry, Sarah, Nancy, Fred, Margaret, William, Caroline, and John.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence to and from members of the Bohna family in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. The letters document daily life of various members of the Bohna family, who were chiefly farmers in Kern County, California, and in Clackamas County, Oregon. In addition to members of the Bohna family, principal correspondents include S. W. Woody and other members of the Woody family, of Woody, California.
Accompanied by Big Sagebrush Valley Ranch Under the Rims, by James E. Bohna (self-published in 1982), a family history.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by author. Unidentified correspondence and other family papers are filed at the end.
Blacksmiths -- California; Blacksmiths -- Oregon; Farmers -- California -- Kern County; Farmers -- Oregon -- Clackamas County; Frontier and pioneer life -- California; Frontier and pioneer life -- Oregon; Clackamas County (Or.) -- Social life and customs; Kern County (Calif.) -- Social life and customs; Wasco County (Or.) -- Social life and customs; Willamette River Valley (Or.) -- Social life and customs; Blacksmiths -- California -- 19th century; Blacksmiths -- Oregon -- 19th century; Farmers -- California -- Kern County; Farmers -- Oregon -- Clackamas County; Bohna, Christian, 1805-1872; Bohna, Ernest; Bohna, Henry Walter; Bohna, James E.; Bohna family; Woody, Spurrell W.
- Bohna Family Correspondence
  - Barkhuft, Maria, 1909-1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biggs, Hannah, 1900-1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biggs, Maud, 1901-1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bohna, Annie, 1883-1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Related Materials
    See also: Bohna, Henry
  - Bohna, Birdie, 1893-1901 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bohna, Ed, 1898-1906, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bohna, Ernest, 1897-1907, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bohna, F.A., 1882-1907, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bohna, Henry, 1873-1902, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Bohna, Henry Walter Scott, 1898-1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bohna, Irena, 1892-1898, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bohna, James Everett, 1882, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bohna, Laurena, 1889-1898, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bohna, Madge, 1897-1899 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bohna, Margaret, 1896-1910 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bohna, Myrtle, 1907-1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bohna, Nettie Woody, 1881-1911 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bohna, T. J., 1892-1920, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bohna, Thomas, 1892-1912 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bohna, Walter, 1896-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bohna, William, 1901-1911, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bonney, Mollie, 1897-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    See also: Bonney, William
  - Bonney, William, 1898-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - "Caroline", 1900-1911 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dooey, O. D., 1898, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Elliott, E. J., 1897-1910 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Elliott, Nellie, 1908-1909, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Elmer", 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Eunice", 1908-1912, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Eveline", 1907-1909 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Fannie", 1892-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Farmer's Fire Relief Association, 1906-1909, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Father", 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Fraser, Margaret, 1900-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Fred", 1910-1919 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Gardett, Evalena Bohna, 1898-1910 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Justice, Rhoda, 1901-1903 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Kennedy, Echo, 1901-1907 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Kennedy, Eunice, 1897-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Kennedy, S. E., 1897-1900 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - "L. B.", 1896-1899 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Langrell, Clara, 1894-1909, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Louisa", 1910 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Mancy, Anna, 1898-1899 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Minie", 1901-1903, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "Nan", 1905-1918, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Odile", 1901-1905 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Osburn, F. M., 1873 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Osburn, Mamie, 1906-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Osburn, Nettie, 1893-1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Osburn, Robert, 1906-1907 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Osburn, William, 1887-1905 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Qualls, F. S., 1903-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Qualls, Minnie Bohna, 1889-1912, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Rena", 1892-1912, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Smith, Nancy, 1891-1911, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Stallcuf, Mary, 1897-1900 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - "Winnefred", 1905-1906 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Woody, S. W., 1871-1910, undated (Box 4, Folder 62-63)
  - Woody, Sarah, 1872-1906, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Woody, Stonewall A., 1899-1905 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - General Correspondence, 1869-1921, undated (Box 4, Folder 66-68)
  - Unidentified fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Personal papers and ephemera, 1892-1925, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Accompanying material
  - Big Sagebrush Valley Ranch Under the Rims / James E. Bohna, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 71)